# **Alaina Kafkes**

#### **Awards**

## Anita Borg Institute GHC Scholar

**June 2016.** Won an all-expenses paid trip to the Grace Hopper Celebration for excellence in innovation & leadership.

#### PanHellenic Scholar

**May 2016.** Received a merit scholarship that honors exceptional undergraduates of Greek-American heritage.

# Personal Projects

#### **TweetFund**

#### August 2016 - Present.

Creating a Chrome extension that facilitates donations to causes that are trending hashtags. Technologies used: JavaScript.

#### Myrror

## January 2016 - Present.

Developed and cast a web app onto a twoway mirror in order to assess young adult body confidence using the principles of social comparison theory. Pitched proof of concept to 50+ students and professors. Currently revamping the interface with the intent of publishing a paper. Technologies used: JavaScript, JQuery, Firebase API.

#### Dibz

#### January 2016 – June 2016.

Founded and developed a web app that offers online sellers the ability to generate a bitlink to share a listing in informal, online communities. Launched to 50+ beta testers. Technologies used: JavaScript, RiotJS, Firebase API, HTML/CSS.

#### Rude

## February 2016 (HackIllinois).

Coded Android app that encourages users to spend quality time socializing without checking their phone. Technologies used: Java, Facebook API.

## Education

Northwestern University | Computer Science, minor in Chemistry Bachelor's Degree Anticipated June 2017. Cumulative GPA: 3.69/4.00

# Work Experience

## Delta Lab | iOS Developer & UX Researcher

**September 2016 – Present.** Building an iOS app that helps users build habits in running and meditation while simultaneously crowdsourcing data about their surroundings. Languages used: Swift.

# Clarifai | Champion (Remote Developer Evangelist)

**August 2016 – Present.** Presented introduction to APIs lecture & Twitter Bot tutorial to 140+ viewers on YouTube Live. Will code projects that showcase the Clarifai API, host more in-person and online talks, and maintain a tech blog. Technologies used: Python, Twitter API.

# GE Healthcare | Software Engineering Intern

June 2016 – August 2016. Contributed 300+ lines of code to the Media Manager web app, which expedites the binding of images & videos to patient data in a vendor-neutral archive. Spearheaded the creation of a mock server to prevent end-to-end testing with sensitive patient information. Technologies used: AngularJS 2, NodeJS, ExpressJS, TypeScript, HTML/CSS.

#### Northwestern University | Teaching Assistant

**December 2015 – Present.** Assists students in an introductory programming course through the creation of a network and with object-oriented programming questions. Languages used: C++.

## Extracurriculars & Offices Held

#### Women in Computing | Internal President

**April 2015 – Present.** Established first-ever mentorship program for undergraduate & graduate women in tech, with 40+ participants in the pilot program. Organizes and teaches at weekly, campus hack nights with 100+ attendees. Founded BuildHer women's hackathon, projected for April 2017.

## EPIC | Project Lead & Web Developer

**April 2016 – Present.** Built website for the Northwestern Venture Challenge. Technologies used: Sass, Gulp, JavaScript, HTML/CSS.

## Peer Health Exchange | Senior Health Educator

**September 2014 – May 2016.** Taught the ninth grade health & sexual education curriculum at Chicago Public Schools.